Good afternoon everyone
大家下午好
So today we're going to transition into a topic that
所以今天我们将转变为一个主题
To me is sort of the reward for having slugged through all the low-level stuff you've done up to this point
对我来说，这是一种奖励，因为你已经完成了迄今为止所做的所有低级别的工作
To be able to really understand and become adept at programming network software
能够真正理解并擅长编程网络软件
Now there's a lot to networking that we're not going to cover
现在网络上有很多我们不会涉及的内容
But at least to have some familiarity with it
但至少要熟悉它
So I know that a lot of you are sort of in the midst of trying to figure out
所以我知道你很多人都想要弄明白
How to make malloc run and make it run fast
如何使malloc运行并使其快速运行
And so this topic is really more pointing toward the future
因此，这个主题更加注重未来
But it's very relevant to the final web lab you'll do for the course
但它与你为该课程所做的最终网络实验室非常相关
And so we're starting to get ready for that
所以我们开始为此做好准备
So like I said this course is not really a full course in networking
就像我说的那样，这门课程并不是一个完整的网络课程
There's many other courses at the university that are
大学还有很多其他课程
And so what we're going to try and do is give you just a little flavor of it
所以我们要尝试做的就是给你一点点味道
And particularly as everything in the course of programmers perspective
特别是作为程序员视角的一切
So how you as a software developer would make use of the C level api's that are relevant to network programming
因此，作为软件开发人员，你将如何利用与网络编程相关的C级API
And why isn't this working
为什么这不起作用
Okay so
可以，然后呢
The idea behind most networking systems is what's called  the client-server model
大多数网络系统背后的想法是所谓的客户端 - 服务器模型
And the idea is that there's a service out there that you want access to
我们的想法是，你需要访问的服务
And you as a customer or a client are making a request to that server
而你作为客户或客户正在向该服务器发出请求
So an example would be when you order something on amazon
所以当你在亚马逊上订购东西时就是一个例子
Amazon has a bunch of servers
亚马逊有很多服务器
And you go to your web browser and contacts the amazon a web server
然后你去你的网络浏览器并联系亚马逊网络服务器
And you make transactions you request something you provide information
并且你在交易时要求提供信息
And it gives you back pretty pictures of things you might want to buy
它会为你提供你可能想要购买的漂亮照片
It acknowledges your credit card transactions
它承认你的信用卡交易
Those are all very classic client-server types of interactions
这些都是非常经典的客户端 - 服务器类型的交互
You as the client,amazon is the server
你作为客户端，亚马逊是服务器
Another interesting example is a telephone
另一个有趣的例子是电话
So if you think about it a telephone is both a client and a server in that
所以如果你考虑一下，电话既是客户又是服务器
When I'm making a placing a call to somebody else
当我打电话给别人时
I'm the client and that person's phone is the server right
我是客户端，那个人的电话就是服务器权利
It's sitting there waiting for calls to come in
它正坐在那里等待来电
And when that call comes in it makes a connection
当那个电话进来时它会建立联系
We talk over the phone and then I hang up either side hangs up
我们通过电话交谈，然后我挂断了任何一方挂断电话
So there's a lot of instances out there of some variation of client and server
因此，客户端和服务器的某些变体有很多实例
And it's a much richer idea in that you can often switch back and forth  the roles of those two parties
这是一个更丰富的想法，因为你经常可以来回切换这两方的角色
But it's a pretty universal and a ubiquitous way of thinking about how to set up a network system
但它是一种非常普遍且无处不在的思考如何建立网络系统的方式
So in general then the idea is that there's a...system working
所以一般来说，这个想法就是......系统正在运行
The client is making some requests to the server
客户端正在向服务器发出一些请求
The server does something locally to deal with it
服务器在本地执行某些操作来处理它
It receive it gets information that retrieves from its database the things you might want to buy
它接收它获取的信息，从其数据库中检索你可能想要购买的东西
And then it sends back information say a nicely formatted a web page with all kinds of shopping suggestions
然后它发回信息说一个格式很好的网页，上面有各种购物建议
And then the client decides what to do next
然后客户决定下一步该做什么
So from a hardware perspective the
所以从硬件角度来看
Interface to a between the network and
网络与网络之间的接口
Your computer is called the NIC or network interface card even though it's not always on a card
你的计算机称为NIC或网络接口卡，即使它并非总是在卡上
And we really won't talk about hardware at all
我们真的不会谈论硬件
But what's most interesting from it is that
但最令人感兴趣的是
It looks to your computer like an I/O device
它看起来像你的计算机I / O设备
And in fact the UNIX of api for dealing with networks
事实上，用于处理网络的api的UNIX
Makes it look like a file
使它看起来像一个文件
So in particular just as a disk sits off of a bus
所以特别是当磁盘离开总线时
And you write data to a disk
并且你将数据写入磁盘
Or you read it from a disk
或者你从磁盘上读取它
Similarly the network sits of a similar bus
类似地，网络位于类似的总线上
And when you want to send a message you actually do it by writing
当你想发送信息时，你实际上是通过写作来实现的
To a sort of virtual file that's called the network
对于一种称为网络的虚拟文件
And if you want...when you're receiving data you do it by reading
如果你想...当你收到数据时，你可以通过阅读来实现
So just as several weeks ago I gave the lecture on I/O
就像几个星期前我就I / O进行了演讲
It turns out that it's extremely relevant to network programming
事实证明，它与网络编程非常相关
That's the basic model that was created by the early developers of the sort of standard UNIX
这是由标准UNIX的早期开发人员创建的基本模型
And now that's carried over not just to UNIX but it's the same model for windows and other operating systems
现在，这不仅仅延续到UNIX，而且它与Windows和其他操作系统的模型相同
So
所以
And now let's just talk a little about what computer networking means
现在让我们谈谈计算机网络的意义
The idea of a network is a collection of systems that are referred to as hosts
网络的概念是被称为主机的系统的集合
That are able to communicate with each other over some kind of communication fabric let's call
这可以通过某种通信结构让我们彼此通信
It communications system
它是通讯系统
And they're sort of partitioned into
它们有点被划分为
Mostly referred to as lands or local area networks
主要称为陆地或局域网
That you establish within a small region
你在一个小区域内建立
And then a wide area network which would be over something the size of a city or perhaps more
然后是一个广阔的区域网络，可能超过一个城市或更大的东西
And over a enterprise such as CMU it's a very complex set of
而对于像CMU这样的企业来说，它是一个非常复杂的组合
For example there's wireless base stations that right in this room
例如，这个房间里就有无线基站
That you're interacting with when you're using a wireless system or your your phone
当你使用无线系统或手机时，你正在与之交互
And then there's a whole networking infrastructure within the university
然后在大学里面有一个完整的网络基础设施
The then goes to some commercial providers
然后去一些商业提供商
At&t in particular that give it access to the commercial internet
特别是，它可以访问商业互联网
And then there's another set of network connections hosted by the supercomputing center
然后是超级计算中心托管的另一组网络连接
That give you access to what's called internet 2 which is the resource that's used for communicating among universities
这使你可以访问所谓的互联网2，这是用于大学之间通信的资源
So underneath you know when you're doing your networking stuff
所以你知道什么时候你正在做你的网络工作
There's this amazingly complex combination of things going on
这种惊人的复杂组合正在进行中
The idea of an internet is supposed is refers to the idea
假设互联网的概念是指这个想法
The general idea of a network of networks
网络网络的总体思路
Taking for example the local area network that this base station provides
以该基站提供的局域网为例
And connecting it up to other networks on campus and across the world
并将其连接到校园和世界各地的其他网络
And when we refer to the capital i internet
当我们提到首都互联网时
That refers to the one instance the most significant instance of an internet
这指的是互联网最重要的一个实例
So i means the sort of general idea of creating a network of networks
所以我的意思是创建网络网络的一般概念
Uppercase i(I) is the specific example that we all know and use all the time
大写i（I）是我们都知道并且一直使用的具体示例
That's organized by a certain set of principles that uses a particular set of protocols and so forth
这是由一组使用特定协议等的原则组织的
And of course we tend to just talk the internet
当然，我们倾向于只谈互联网
And most people know that what that really implies is the sort of existing network structure that there is
大多数人都知道，真正意味着现有的网络结构
And that's good enough for the purpose of this course
这对于本课程来说已经足够了
We're not going to talk much about other possible designs one might have for a network
我们不打算谈论可能为网络设计的其他可能的设计
So most of the low level networking is supported by something called Ethernet
因此大多数低级网络都被称为以太网的东西支持
And the term Ethernet actually has evolved tremendously over time
以太网这个术语实际上随着时间的推移发展得非常迅速
So that it's almost more like a brand name that it is in specific technology
因此它几乎更像是一个品牌名称，它在特定的技术中
And the version you're familiar with the wired version of it
你熟悉它的有线版本的版本
You have a wire to some sort of a box
你有一个电线到某种盒子
Like that you plug the your Ethernet jacks into
就像你插入以太网插孔一样
And historically those were called hubs
历史上那些被称为枢纽
And the idea of a hub, it was just a repeater that whatever came into it from one computer
而对于一个集线器的想法，它只是一个转发器，无论从一台计算机进入它
It would broadcast to all the connected machines
它将广播到所有连接的机器
And so you only want to do this for maybe a dozen or
所以你只想做十几个或者那个
So machines that it's like a party-line they're all hearing what everybody else is saying
所以机器就像派对线一样，他们都听到了其他人所说的话
And in fact the original first version the Ethernet did that by everyone interacting over a single cable
事实上，以太网最初的第一个版本是由每个人通过单根电缆进行交互而实现的
Carrying essentially radio signals and
基本上承载无线电信号和
And similarly when you're in this room using a wireless internet
同样，当你在这个房间使用无线互联网时
A wireless internet is sort of like a hub and that
无线互联网有点像集线器
All the packets that you're sending all across the room
你在整个房间发送的所有数据包
They're all sort of making use of the same radio frequencies the same communication channel
他们都使用相同的无线电频率和相同的通信频道
And there's a protocol for how they detect when two messages get set at the same time and therefore interfere with each other
并且有一个协议，用于检测两个消息何时同时设置并因此相互干扰
So that can only sort of scale up to maybe at most a hundred different
所以这只能扩展到最多可能达到一百种不同
Hosts communicating because they're all sharing a single communication channel
主持通信，因为它们都共享一个通信通道
Now in the wired world what's evolved is usually when you buy a box
现在在有线世界中，通常在你购买盒子时会发展
Or you get one from your cable company
或者你从有线电视公司那里得到一个
With all those ports in it, it's actually called a router or sometimes a switch in that
有了所有这些端口，它实际上被称为路由器或有时称为交换机
It doesn't broadcast to everyone
它不向所有人广播
It selectively tries to guess
它有选择地试图猜测
Is this particular message bound for this particular host
此特定邮件是否绑定到此特定主机
And only send to that one
只发送给那个
And as you know you can take these and wire up
如你所知，你可以把它们连接起来
I think about up to 6 levels deep in and hub
我认为最多有6个级别和hub
And basically create a network of wired connections
并且基本上创建了有线连接网络
And they'll all get from one to the other somehow
他们都会以某种方式从一个到另一个
And then after that it gets more complicated you can add more sophisticated types of switching on top of it
然后，它会变得更加复杂，你可以在其上添加更复杂的切换类型
But so the general idea of even an Ethernet is actually a fairly complex thing
但是，甚至以太网的总体思路实际上也是一件相当复杂的事情
But it's some sort of conceptual level we can just think of it as a bunch of hosts
但它是某种概念层面我们可以把它想象成一堆主机
That can talk directly to one another
这可以直接相互对话
And then an internet then refers to the idea of taking those local area networks and connecting them together
然后互联网就是指采用这些局域网并将它们连接在一起的想法
Via routers and routers obey a particular protocol based on the address
通过路由器和路由器遵循基于地址的特定协议
That you're trying to send data to
你正在尝试将数据发送到
And
和
And so what you end up with conceptually is a whole bunch of hosts spread potentially all across the world
因此，你最终在概念上最终会在全世界范围内传播一大堆主机
And then some magical system of routers
然后是一些神奇的路由器系统
That will get a message from one place to the other
这将从一个地方到另一个地方收到消息
Based on a mode of addressing where there's some known address of the hosts
基于寻址模式，其中存在一些已知的主机地址
That you're trying to send to
那你要发送给
And it will hub through multiple routers to get from one place to the other
它将通过多个路由器集中到一个地方到另一个地方
And that's true whether it's on campus
这是真的，无论是在校园里
Or whether it's hopping all the way around the world
或者它是否一直在世界各地跳跃
And so again there's this huge body of information and knowledge about how that routing works
因此，有关该路由如何工作的大量信息和知识
And how its reliable and all that
它的可靠性如何
But we're going to just assume that somebody else has figured that out
但我们只是假设其他人已经想到了这一点
And our job as programmers is just to be able to communicate from one host to another
我们作为程序员的工作就是能够从一个主机到另一个主机进行通信
And so how could you design a system where all these diverse systems
那么你怎么能设计一个所有这些不同系统的系统
Made by computers made by different manufacturers operating under different countries with different telecommunications bodies governing bodies and so forth
由在不同国家运营的不同制造商制造的计算机制造，具有不同的电信机构管理机构等
How can they all work with each other
他们怎么能互相合作
And the requirement is you have to have a protocol you have to have some common set of conventions
要求是你必须有一个协议，你必须有一些共同的约定
For what messages look like how they get sent
对于什么消息看起来如何发送
What happens if one of them doesn't make it how do you recover from that and so forth
如果他们中的一个没有成功，你会如何从中恢复等等会发生什么
And so what does a protocol include well it has to include some way of naming things so that
所以协议包括什么，它必须包括一些命名事物的方式
If I want to send to some host I have some way of designating
如果我想发送给某些主机我有一些指定方式
Who that host is
谁是主持人
And then there's the routing system has to have some reliable way of getting my data to that named host
然后，路由系统必须有一些可靠的方法将我的数据传送到该命名主机
And that's the delivery mechanism
这就是交付机制
And that's usually done and one of the things that we now accept  as universal
这通常已经完成，我们现在接受的其中一项是普遍的
But it really wasn't when it first came out was idea of you take all your data and you divide it into packets
但它真的不是第一次出现的时候就是你把所有数据都拿出来然后把它分成数据包
And packets are typically about a thousand to two thousand bytes
数据包通常大约一千到两千字节
And so if you have a longer message it chops it up into individual packets and sends it across
因此，如果你有更长的消息，它会将其切换为单个数据包并将其发送出去
And all the communication occurs at the packet level
并且所有通信都发生在数据包级别
That's different than the historic phone system
这与历史悠久的电话系统不同
I was a connection based system meaning that
我是一个基于连接的系统，意思是
If I was calling somebody there is a dedicated wire set of wires maintained by the phone company
如果我打电话给某人，电话公司会维护一条专用的电线
That would be reserved and locked down for our own use
这将被保留并锁定以供我们自己使用
During the entire duration of that phone call
在整个电话通话期间
So
所以
To get them from one host say A to B
从一个主人那里得到他们说A到B.
What happens is we want to send a packet
我们想要发送一个数据包
And that packet will contain some amount of data
该数据包将包含一些数据
And the idea of a packet communication then is you put little headers on
然后，分组通信的想法是你把小标题放在上面
That contain certain routing information see on the front of an envelope of a letter perhaps
包含某些信息的信封前面可能包含某些路由信息
And so and at different points in the way
所以以及在不同的方式
They'll have different numbers of headers and different protocols or formats for what those headers look like
它们将具有不同数量的标头和不同的协议或格式，以用于这些标头的外观
So in particular within
所以特别是在内
I want to send a message and I'll
我想发一条消息，我会
I'll do that and then the software that runs on my machine that handles this
我会这样做，然后在我的机器上运行的软件处理这个
Will put a header in front of that describes the internet routing
将前面的标题放在描述互联网路由的位置
And then it will tack a header in front of that talks about the local area network routing that gets used
然后，在谈论前面将讨论使用的局域网路由
And that's what's referred to as the a PH the packet header for the internet protocol
这就是所谓的互联网协议的数据包标头
And FH1 the frame header for this particular message being sent within this local network
并且FH1在该本地网络内发送该特定消息的帧头
And then the network interface card or the adapter here
然后是网络接口卡或适配器
Is then responsible for putting that out over this local communication of capability
然后负责将这种能力放在本地通信上
And then that gets received at the other end by the network adapter at the receivers direction
然后，网络适配器在接收方向接收到另一端
It will put up its own frame header on it to pass it in
它将在其上放置自己的帧头以传递它
And that then gets tripped off
然后被绊倒了
So that all hosts be set sees is the the data that gets sent
因此，设置所有主机看到的是发送的数据
But this idea of putting headers in front and at times sort of what they call encapsulation that
但是这种把头放在前面的想法有时与他们所谓的封装有关
I'll take this big packet and I'll just tack some more information on top to the front of it header information
我将采取这个大包，我只是在它的头部信息的前面添加更多信息
And I'll send through the rest of it just as a set of bytes
我将通过其余部分发送，就像一组字节一样
So the internet that we know and love the capital I internet
所以我们知道并喜欢互联网的互联网互联网
Then has a particular set of protocols that are you've probably heard the terms
然后有一组特定的协议，你可能已经听过这些术语
One is called the IP the internet protocol
一个被称为IP的互联网协议
Which is the one that defines ideas about how do you get how do you name hosts on the internet
哪个定义了关于如何获得如何在互联网上命名主机的想法
And how do you send packets
你如何发送数据包
And they're referred to sometimes is datagrams
他们有时提到的是数据报
Meaning that a packet is just a single entity that gets sent from point A to point B
这意味着数据包只是从A点发送到B点的单个实体
And the underlying IP doesn't guarantee delivery so
而基础知识产权并不能保证交付
So it's based on what they call best
所以这是基于他们最好的
Effort communication meaning that at each step along the way
努力沟通意味着在整个过程中的每一步
If for example things are good then it will just send this packet along
例如，如果事情是好的话，它就会发送这个数据包
If there's too much congestion
如果有太多的拥堵
There's been a you know somebody's turned on their microwave oven and
你知道有人打开他们的微波炉和
It's set up some radio frequency interface interference
它设置了一些射频接口干扰
Then at the IP level it just drops that packet and says whoops
然后在IP级别，它只丢弃该数据包并说哎呀
I screwed up sorry it doesn't even say sorry it just does it silently
我搞砸了抱歉它甚至没有说对不起只是默默地说
And then you can as a programmer make use of that very global level
然后你可以作为一个程序员利用这个非常全球化的水平
So normally as a programmer you don't really want to program at that level
所以通常作为一个程序员，你真的不想在那个级别编程
Because you'll send packets and they will get there
因为你会发送数据包，他们会到达那里
But you can if you want to and it's called UDP a protocol
但是你可以，如果你想，它被称为UDP协议
It's just a small software layer over IP
它只是一个基于IP的小软件层
And there's some applications
还有一些应用程序
That you'll see for example in the computer game world where you want to send information really fast and if some information gets dropped it's not a big deal
你会在计算机游戏世界中看到你想要快速发送信息的例子，如果一些信息被丢弃，这不是什么大不了的事
That people actually program at that level
人们实际上在那个级别编程
We won't really talk about that
我们不会真的谈论这个
The more common protocol that gets used and carries 99% of internet traffic is what's called TCP(transmission control protocol)
使用更常见的协议并承载99％的互联网流量就是所谓的TCP（传输控制协议）
And that provides a reliable the equivalent of telephone connection
这提供了相当于电话连接的可靠性
That I can reliably send data from point A to point B
我可以可靠地将数据从A点发送到B点
As many bytes as I like
像我喜欢的那么多字节
It's a guaranteed
这是有保障的
Every it's sometimes fast and sometimes not but it's there
每一次它有时都很快，有时不会，但它就在那里
And it's built on top of the IP of this datagram
它建立在这个数据报的IP之上
Meaning that it has to take whatever you're sending and slice it up into these single packets
这意味着它必须采取你发送的任何内容并将其切片到这些单个数据包中
If one of them doesn't get sent it will resend it until it gets there
如果其中一个没有被发送，它将重新发送它直到它到达那里
They have to deal with the fact that packets can travel different paths and one can get ahead of the other in transmission
他们必须处理这样一个事实，即数据包可以通过不同的路径，并且可以在传输中领先于另一个
And so it has to reorder them in the correct sequence
所以它必须按正确的顺序重新排序
And so there's a lot of stuff under it but
所以它下面有很多东西但是
We'll just assume that it kind of works
我们只是假设它有点工作
And so you can just rely think about it is I have a stream connection
所以你可以依靠它来思考它是否有流连接
I can send from A to B and B can send a stream of data back to me
我可以从A发送到B，B可以向我发送数据流
And we're all happy
我们都很开心
And so that's the version that looks like file I/O
这就是看起来像文件I / O的版本
I just keep writing to a file and it's sending packets over the network to the other end
我只是继续写一个文件，它通过网络发送数据包到另一端
And then the other side can be sending stuff to me
然后另一方可以向我发送东西
And I'm just reading it and I'm just reading bytes of data
而我只是在阅读它，而我只是在阅读数据字节
Not worrying about how that got broken up into individual packets
不用担心如何将其分解为单个数据包
And so that's referred to as the sockets interface
所以这被称为套接字接口
And you'll hear the term socket programming and that's exactly what we're talking about
你会听到套接字编程这个术语，这正是我们所说的
And so from a sort of software system
从某种软件系统来看
Than software hardware system then
然后比软件硬件系统
The client and the server are both implemented as application programs
客户端和服务器都实现为应用程序
At the respective endpoints on their hosts
在其主机上的相应端点
And they make use of software and libraries that run at some combination of the user level and at the kernel level
并且他们使用在用户级别和内核级别的某种组合运行的软件和库
And therefore I have access to direct resources
因此我可以获得直接资源
And so
所以
I is a program or an application programmer then make use of this software api
我是一个程序或应用程序员然后使用这个软件API
That lets me do socket programming
这让我可以做套接字编程
And it's based on gives directly supports TCP/IP
它基于直接支持TCP / IP
So first of all we're going to talk most of the time about what's called IPV4
首先，我们大部分时间都会谈论所谓的IPV4
A version 4 which is the one that's been running for since the 1980s I think early 1980s
从20世纪80年代早期开始，我认为是一个版本4，它是自20世纪80年代早期以来一直在运行的版本
And is this the standard and we'll talk very only mentioned very briefly the idea of what's called IPV6
这是标准，我们只会简单地谈谈所谓的IPV6的想法
Which is sort of a next-generation version
哪种是下一代版本
So the idea of a IPV4 and this is now we're talking about IP
所以IPV4的想法现在我们正在讨论IP
And and this is true of TCP as well is that an address is actually just 32 bits
并且TCP也是如此，地址实际上只是32位
But it's usually expressed in what they call dotted decimal form
但它通常用他们称之为点分十进制形式表示
And you've seen these addresses before
你以前见过这些地址
That it's 4 decimal numbers
这是4个十进制数
And they can only range between 0 and 255
它们只能在0到255之间
Because each one of them is a single bytes worth of information
因为它们中的每一个都是单个字节的信息
So we're used to writing things in hex now in this course
因此，我们习惯于在本课程中以十六进制编写内容
But we're going to write it as each byte is written as a decimal digit
但是我们要把它写成每个字节写成十进制数字
And they're actually passed and stored in
它们实际上是通过并存储的
What's called network byte order which is big endian byte order
什么叫做大字节字节顺序的网络字节顺序
And so we have to worry about the whole big endian vs. good endian thing
所以我们不得不担心整个大端和好端的事情
When we're doing network programming
当我们进行网络编程时
And you can actually learn a lot there's a whole levels of how the different bytes mean
实际上你可以学到很多不同字节的含义
But for example any ip address it starts with 128.2.  is at CMU
但是例如任何ip地址都以128.2开头。在CMU
I think and then
我想，然后
And so essentially CMU owns that part of the IP address space
因此，基本上CMU拥有IP地址空间的那部分
Which if you think about that's approximately 2^64
如果你认为这大约是2 ^ 64
2 to the...no,not 2^6,2^16 different IP addresses available for use by campus
2到...不，不是2 ^ 6,2 ^ 16个不同的IP地址可供校园使用
And as I mentioned there's a newer version called IPv6
正如我所提到的那样，有一个名为IPv6的新版本
That gives you a 128-bit addresses
这给你一个128位的地址
You can imagine actually that if you think about how many nodes are there in the internet
实际上你可以想象，如果你想到互联网中有多少个节点
If a 4 byte address is only to the 32 so that's 4 billion
如果一个4字节的地址只有32个那么就是40亿
And I don't know about you but I have a lot of different things that use IP
我不了解你，但我有很多不同的东西使用IP
I have a phone,I have two laptops,I have a couple desktops
我有一部手机，我有两台笔记本电脑，我有几台台式机
So if all of..if every one of us used multiple IP addresses then actually the world would be out of them right
因此，如果我们每个人都使用多个IP地址，那么实际上世界将是正确的
There's seven billion people in the world not all of whom have access to the internet
世界上有70亿人并非所有人都可以访问互联网
But a large fraction of them do
但其中很大一部分都有
And so there's a whole kind of crazy way of dealing with the multitude of possible IP addresses
因此，有一种处理大量可能IP地址的疯狂方式
So the obvious thing would be well let's just allocate a lot more addresses
所以显而易见的事情就是让我们分配更多的地址
And jump let's just skip 64 bits and go right to 128 and that's the idea behind IPv6
跳转让我们跳过64位然后直到128，这就是IPv6背后的想法
But quite honestly this has been one of those technologies that's been out there for over 15 years
但老实说，这已经是那些已经存在超过15年的技术之一
And still has a very low level of adoption so
并且仍然具有非常低的采用率
It's still a future technology
它仍然是未来的技术
People have basically figured out all these crazy schemes to make use of just stick within the 4 byte limit
人们基本上已经找到了所有这些疯狂的方案，只使用4字节限制
Okay so let's start talking the program the sort of programmer perspective on this
好的，让我们开始讨论程序员对此的看法
And this is one area where you'll wish you weren't programming in C
这是一个你希望你不用C语言编程的领域
But you are
但你是
So there's a lot of really crufty stuff
所以有很多非常苛刻的东西
And it was all developed most of the software protocols were conceived before C even was what it is today
所有开发的大部分软件协议都是在C甚至是今天之前构思出来的
So like the Kernighan and Ritchie book you have is called the second edition
所以像Kernighan和Ritchie这本书一样被称为第二版
And it's based on what was called ANSI C or ISO C
它基于所谓的ANSI C或ISO C.
But these all date before that they date back to the original Kernighan and Ritchie
但是这些都是在他们追溯到最初的Kernighan和Ritchie之前
So for example void* did not exist in that era
因此，例如在那个时代不存在void *
And so you use char * as a generic pointer
所以你使用char *作为通用指针
And so there's just a lot of stuff in this programming
所以这个编程中有很多东西
Interface where you go wow that is really crufty and that that truth is yes you're right
你哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇哇
So in particular there's a lot of different structures that are defined and
所以特别是定义了很多不同的结构
One of them is called an in_addr which means internet address
其中一个叫做in_addr，意思是互联网地址
And it's just defined to be a 32-bit unsigned number
它只是被定义为32位无符号数
And in general as I mentioned there
就像我在那里提到的那样
The so called network byte order whoever designed the original protocols was a fan of big endian addressing
所谓的网络字节顺序无论谁设计了原始协议，都是大端寻址的粉丝
And so that's what it is even though actually most of the machines that are out there in this world are little endian
事实就是如此，即使实际上这个世界上大多数机器都是小端的
And so there's a set of standard library functions
所以有一套标准的库函数
That you use to convert between network order and host order
你用于在网络订​​单和主机订单之间进行转换
And the idea of it is now if I run my software on a little endian or a big endian machine
如果我在一个小端或大端机器上运行我的软件，那么它的想法就是现在
These functions will do the right thing
这些功能将做正确的事情
So if I just use these standard libraries
所以，如果我只是使用这些标准库
Then I don't have to worry about porting it every time I change the word ordering of a machine
然后，每次我更改机器的字顺序时，我都不必担心移植它
One of the things you'll notice here is
你会注意到的一件事是
There is no function to convert 64-bit data between a network order and host order so
没有在网络订单和主机订单之间转换64位数据的功能
I don't know what people do when I do it I just write my own saw,my own to do it
我不知道人们在做什么时会做什么我只是写自己的锯，我自己做
Or I don't because I know my other end is a little endian machine
或者我没有，因为我知道我的另一端是一个小端机器
So anyways these are already some functions you'll start seeing for that look like network conversion software
所以无论如何，这些已经是你将开始看到的一些功能，就像网络转换软件一样
And as I mentioned the addresses are written in a dotted decimal form
正如我所提到的，地址是以点分十进制形式写的
And it's also big endian
它也是大端
So if I were to write in hex 128 is of course 0x80
所以如果我用十六进制写128当然是0x80
So that's the most significant byte of the IP address
这是IP地址中最重要的字节
And then there is a set of functions api calls you can use to convert between this dotted decimal format
然后有一组函数api调用，你可以使用它们在这个点分十进制格式之间进行转换
And the actual just a 32-bit unsigned int
而实际只是一个32位的unsigned int
And actually it used to be there is
实际上它曾经存在
You might see some older presentations where they use different names for this
你可能会看到一些较旧的演示文稿，其中使用了不同的名称
But the most recent version api calls this
但是最新版本的api称之为
The presentation version the dotted decimal they referred to it as a presentation
演示版本点缀小数，他们称之为演示文稿
Then you can look up the and it's in the book to what the calls to these look like
然后你可以查看书中的内容，看看它们的调用是什么样的
But you probably don't or very seldom
但你可能不会或很少
When you're thinking about I want to go to Google
当你想到我想去谷歌的时候
You don't think about what its IP address is you just go to www.google.com
你只需访问www.google.com即可考虑其IP地址
And for everything you do you refer to it by this
对于你所做的一切，你都可以参考它
It would have referred called internet domain names which is a hierarchical naming system
它会称为互联网域名，这是一个分层命名系统
Whereas you know there's .edu is for educational institutions
虽然你知道.edu是教育机构
.com is for commercial
.com是商业用途
.net is general networking of many countries have their own suffix
.net是许多国家的通用网络都有自己的后缀
So you know .de is for Germany and so forth
所以你知道.de是德国等等
And so those are called the first level domain names
所以那些被称为一级域名
And then there's a hierarchical naming structure under that
然后在那下面有一个分层的命名结构
And
和
There's actually an interesting question of okay
实际上有一个有趣的问题
How do I then map from those hierarchical names those domain names into this dotted decimal or the 32 bit IP address
然后，我如何从这些分层名称将这些域名映射到此点分十进制或32位IP地址
And the job of that is by a very large distributed system called the DNS the domain name system
而这个工作就是由一个非常大的分布式系统称为DNS域名系统
Where the only sort of centrally managed part of it is at the top level
其中唯一的集中管理部分位于顶层
So for each of these first level domain names
因此，对于这些一级域名中的每一个
There's a collection a very large collection of machines that keep track of all the IP addresses
有一个非常大的机器集合，可以跟踪所有IP地址
That map to one of those first level domain names
该映射到其中一个第一级域名
And then for example CMU maintains its own naming authority
然后例如CMU维护自己的命名权限
So anything that says something .cmu.edu
所以任何东西都说.cmu.edu
There's local DNS servers within CMU
CMU中有本地DNS服务器
That are picking apart ok where should you know
这是分开确定你应该知道哪里
If I say cs.cum.edu what would be the IP address for that
如果我说cs.cum.edu那将是什么IP地址
Well and it's actually pretty interesting how this is managed because it's all it's totally decentralized
嗯，这实际上非常有趣，因为它完全是分散的
There's a whole set of protocols that govern how naming is done
有一整套协议可以控制命名的完成方式
But conceptually we can think of it as just this big database
但从概念上讲，我们可以将其视为这个大数据库
That gives me a mapping
这给了我一个映射
Where I can give a domain name and it will get back to me a one or more IP addresses
在哪里我可以提供一个域名，它会回复给我一个或多个IP地址
I can give an IP address and it will come back with one or more domain names
我可以提供一个IP地址，它将返回一个或多个域名
Oh and so there's actually an application you can run
哦，所以实际上你可以运行一个应用程序
On most machines called nslookup and there's another one called dig
在大多数名为nslookup的机器上，还有一个名为dig的机器
That you can use to find basically probe the DNS
你可以用来查找基本探测DNS
And find in either direction you can look at the given a domain name you can find its IP address
并找到任何一个方向，你可以查看给定的域名，你可以找到它的IP地址
Given an IP address you can find its domain name
给定IP地址，你可以找到其域名
And we also I'll show you some code that
我们还会向你展示一些代码
Just as an example of how you do the programming
就像你如何编程一样
I'll just show that momentarily called hostname
我只是简单地说明了这个主机名
So just some examples
所以只是一些例子
You know if I look up some address like the website for the computer science school computer science
你知道我是否在查找计算机科学学院计算机科学网站的地址
Using nslookup
使用nslookup
It comes back can people see this okay
它回来后可以让人看到这个没关系
Doing it bigger?It's okay
做得更大？没关系
So this is what nslookup like and this stuff here just tells you
所以这就是nslookup所喜欢的，这里的内容告诉你
You know who where was the actual directory entry in the which DNS  server actually gave this information back
你知道哪个DNS服务器实际提供此信息的实际目录条目在哪里
And it says that
它说
www.cs.cum is actually a synonym for a weirder one called WEB-LB.SRV.cum.edu
www.cs.cum实际上是一个名为WEB-LB.SRV.cum.edu的奇怪的同义词
And its IP address is 128.2 like you'd expect
它的IP地址是128.2，就像你期望的那样
217.13
And of course that works not just at CMU but I can
当然，这不仅仅适用于CMU，但我可以
You know go ask about what Stanford is up to
你知道去问斯坦福大学的目标
And it will come back and its IP addresses of something 171.64
它会回来，其IP地址为171.64
And that's been managed by that and you'll see again it's
那是由那管理的，你会再次看到它
I asked for www.cs.stanford.edu it said well the real name of that is cs.stanford.edu
我要求www.cs.stanford.edu它说得好，真正的名字是cs.stanford.edu
And this actually is a point that the
而这实际上是一个点
The mapping between domain names
域名之间的映射
And internet addresses is not one-to-one
互联网地址不是一对一的
You can have multiple domain names that refer to the same internet address
你可以拥有多个引用相同Internet地址的域名
But you can also have multiple internet addresses
但你也可以拥有多个互联网地址
Excuse me
打扰一下
That's weird
这很奇怪
So like twitter.com when I ask for it it comes back with four different addresses
就像twitter.com一样，当我要求它时，它会返回四个不同的地址
And if I do the exact same thing again
如果我再做同样的事情
Mmm came back but yeah
嗯回来了，但是
You see it came back with
你看它回来了
The same no not even the same addresses
同样没有甚至不同的地址
It came back for example here the one that ends with .6 that wasn't in that first was
例如，它回来了以.6结尾的那个不是第一个的
So it came back with a slightly different set of addresses and a somewhat different order
所以它回来时的地址略有不同，订单也有所不同
And the idea of that is that actually has multiple servers
而这个想法实际上是有多个服务器
So when I send to twitter.com or Google or any of these major servers
所以当我发送到twitter.com或Google或任何这些主要服务器时
There's not just one place in the internet that's handling everybody's google traffic
互联网上不只有一个地方处理每个人的谷歌流量
Through thousands of places spread around the world
通过遍布世界各地的数千个地方
And the way they get you there is by playing tricks with the DNS
他们让你到达那里的方式是通过DNS玩弄技巧
That Google is constantly sending updates to the it maintains its own DNS servers
Google不断向其发送更新，维护自己的DNS服务器
So it's constantly changing them
所以它不断改变它们
And it will actually give you different addresses depending on where in the world you're located as well
它实际上会根据你所在的世界位置为你提供不同的地址
To try and provide a server that's sort of reasonably close to you geographically so
尝试提供一种在地理位置上合理接近你的服务器
There's all just all kinds of tricks that happen through DNS
所有这些都是通过DNS发生的技巧
That is part of the way they can sort of manage this huge set of addresses
这是他们管理这一大量地址的方式的一部分
And then there's some other domain names that don't have any IP address
然后还有一些其他域名没有任何IP地址
That they're somewhere in the hierarchy that hierarchical naming system
他们在层次结构命名系统的层次结构中
But they're not actually referring to a particular host
但他们实际上并不是指特定的主持人
So it's a multi multi mapping
所以这是一个多重映射
In the...the api set reflects
在......中，api集反映出来
It so this is just going what I told you they sometimes one-to-one
所以这就是我告诉你他们有时一对一的事情
Sometimes many domain names refer to the same address
有时许多域名引用相同的地址
Sometimes of one name maps to multiple addresses that change over time
有时，一个名称会映射到多个随时间变化的地址
And then there's some where it's a valid name
然后有一些地方是有效的名字
But it doesn't have an IP address it doesn't have a host associated with a question
但它没有IP地址，它没有与问题相关的主机
[student speaking]
How do I get...how do you get your own IP address
我怎么得到......你如何获得自己的IP地址
Well all you have to beg borrow or you have to either borrow or buy them
那么你只需要借钱，或者你必须借或买它们
So for example at CMU there is some number of what they call statically allocated ip addresses
因此，例如在CMU，有一些他们称之为静态分配的IP地址
Where it's just fixed assigned to that machine and you can register form and request them through computing services
只需将其固定分配给该机器，你就可以注册表单并通过计算服务请求它们
But most you don't have that most you get one that's I signed dynamically
但大多数人没有那么多，你得到的是我动态签名的那个
So there's a pool of addresses that you basically they call them leasing
所以有一个地址池，你基本上他们称之为租赁
That you are assigned with for a while
你被分配了一段时间
And then but it could possibly be reassigned to someone else
然后它可能会被重新分配给其他人
And that's part of the way it can manage
这是它可以管理的方式的一部分
You know somewhat limited set of IP addresses
你知道一些有限的IP地址
So the idea of like I said that the main
所以这个想法就像我说的那样主要
A way we'll think about it is in terms of what's called TCP
我们将考虑的方式就是所谓的TCP
And it says connection oriented protocol
它说面向连接的协议
Where I establish a connection from one host establishes a connection to another host
我从一个主机建立连接的位置建立与另一个主机的连接
And they can communicate to each other sending arbitrarily long streams of bytes to each other
并且它们可以相互通信，相互之间发送任意长的字节流
And so the connection is then two hosts that can talk to each other
因此，连接是两个可以相互通信的主机
And each of those endpoints is referred to as a socket
每个端点都称为套接字
And so I can and a socket is both an IP address
所以我可以和一个套接字都是一个IP地址
And what's called a port number
什么叫做端口号
So there's a 16 byte, 16 bit number for every connection
因此每个连接都有一个16字节，16位的数字
That's referred to as its port
那被称为它的端口
And the reason for that is just because I'm talking to a particular machine
原因只是因为我正在和一台特定的机器交谈
That machine can support different services
该机器可以支持不同的服务
It can provide SSH connections it can provide FTP connections
它可以提供SSH连接，可以提供FTP连接
It can host a mail server,it can host a web server
它可以托管邮件服务器，它可以托管Web服务器
So a particular machine might have a multitude of different services
因此，特定的机器可能具有多种不同的服务
And so those are differentiated from each other with what are called port numbers
因此，这些与所谓的端口号相互区别
And similarly isaac client might have connections to dozens of hosts going at any given time
同样，isaac客户端可能会在任何给定时间与数十台主机建立连接
I'm cruising the web I'm you know doing all that different stuff
我正在巡航网络我知道你正在做所有不同的事情
And that's all differentiated the client end that there's different ports
这就是客户端区别于不同的端口
Associated with your different programs that are running
与你正在运行的不同程序相关联
And so a port then is a 16-bit integer
所以端口则是16位整数
That identifies which particular endpoint is
这标识了哪个特定端点
Being communicated with it either the client side of the server side
与服务器端的客户端进行通信
And typically at the client side these are assigned dynamically
通常在客户端，这些是动态分配的
And the referred to as ephemeral ports meaning
而称为短暂的港口意义
They only are assigned for the limited duration that you have a connection with that
它们仅在与你有连接的有限时间内分配
That you're maintaining that connection
你正在维持这种联系
And then there has to be some way if I'm going to contact
如果我要联系，那么必须有一些方法
And I want to know the dns will tell me what the IP address is of say google.com
我想知道dns会告诉我google.com的IP地址是什么
But I have to know that
但我必须知道
Am I communicating with its web service which is port 80 or https secure socket is a different report number
我与其Web服务进行通信，即端口80或https安全套接字是不同的报告编号
So which service I'm asking for
那我要求的服务
And there's a standard list what are called well-known ports
还有一个标准列表，称为众所周知的端口
That are that I can contact at the server end to get the particular service I'm looking for
那就是我可以在服务器端联系以获得我正在寻找的特定服务
And those are assigned there's a big waste of port assignments
那些被分配在那里是一个很大的浪费端口分配
And so the again that's part of the sort
所以这又是那种类型的一部分
Of a whole set of internet standards is the identifiers for the different ports
一整套互联网标准是不同端口的标识符
What services those are and how those particular protocols work
这些是什么服务以及这些特定协议如何工作
So when I have a connection then
所以，当我有一个连接然后
As I mentioned I'll think of it as a connection then is as
正如我所提到的，我会把它视为连接然后就是这样
A link between two machines based on some known port typically at the server end
两台计算机之间的链接，基于通常位于服务器端的某些已知端口
And a dynamically assigned or ephemeral port assigned at the client in
并在客户端分配动态分配或临时端口
And I can refer to then that connection then is identified by the combination of the hosts at the two ends
然后我可以参考那个连接然后通过两端主机的组合来识别
And the ports that they're using
以及他们正在使用的端口
And in general then it's the job of the kernel to differentiate the different connections that are coming into a machine
通常情况下，内核的工作是区分进入机器的不同连接
And figure out which software which process to wake up
并找出哪个软件处理唤醒
When a data you know when some data arrives from another machine
当某些数据从另一台机器到达时你知道的数据
In which actual program running on that machine will make use of that data
在该机器上运行的实际程序将使用该数据
And that's done by associating for each of the ports, a particular process executing program
这是通过关联每个端口，特定进程执行程序来完成的
That's going to handle those particular requests
这将处理这些特定请求
And it's totally possible for a client to be interacting with a single server over different ports
并且客户端完全可以通过不同的端口与单个服务器进行交互
But those are considered to be different connections and
但那些被认为是不同的联系和
And so they don't really interfere with each other
所以他们并没有真正互相干扰
So that's what I mentioned is this is what we refer to as sockets programming or the sockets interface
所以我所提到的是这就是我们所说的套接字编程或套接字接口
It was developed sort of as the internet was evolving in the late 70s and early 80s
它的开发有点像互联网在70年代末和80年代初期不断发展
So socket then as I said is certain logically one end
所以socket就像我说的那样在某种程度上是逻辑上的一端
One of the two ends of a connection
连接的两端之一
And from an application point of view you'll see it as a file descriptor
从应用程序的角度来看，你会将其视为文件描述符
Just the low-level file stuff that you've already seen that you can do reading and writing from
只是你已经看过的低级文件，你可以从中读取和写入
Um
一
And so that's the sort of mental model that is provided by the socket interface
这就是套接字接口提供的那种心智模型
But it's a very different you know the actual implementation of network
但是你知道网络的实际实现是非常不同的
When you write to a socket
当你写入套接字时
It's firing up all kinds of network stuff whereas you write to a disk
当你写入磁盘时，它会启动所有类型的网络
It's operating a disk controller
它正在运行磁盘控制器
So at the hardware level and even at the lower levels of software they're very different beasts
因此，在硬件层面，甚至在较低级别的软件中，它们都是非常不同的野兽
But you as an application programmer see some commonality there
但是作为应用程序员，你在那里看到了一些共性
Okay so let's jump right into the API
好的，让我们直接进入API
And again this is a place where you'll wish you were programming in a language
再次，这是一个你希望你用语言编程的地方
That had a type hierarchy
那有一个类型层次结构
But you aren't,you're programming in C
但你不是，你在用C编程
There's a type, there's a zillion struck's that you kind of have to get familiar with
有一种类型，你必须要熟悉它
But one's called a sockaddr and basically it's just a 16 bytes worth of stuff
但是有人称之为sockaddr，基本上它只是一个16字节的东西
Where the only thing that's special here is that the leading two bytes
这里唯一特别的东西是前两个字节
A designate what type of socket this is
A指定这是什么类型的插座
And particularly be different whether it's a TCP socket
特别是它是否是TCP套接字是不同的
An IPv6 socket a UDP socket
IPv6套接字是UDP套接字
And all those will have different numbers
而所有这些都会有不同的数字
A different constant in there that tells you which type of socket it is
那里有一个不同的常量，告诉你它是哪种类型的套接字
And then the high level the sockets in a lot of the programs don't need to know
然后高级别的许多程序中的套接字不需要知道
You know which type of connection this is
你知道这是什么类型的连接
They can just deal with they basically call other software to deal with that
他们可以只处理他们基本上调用其他软件来处理它
So that's why it's referred to as being families specific
所以这就是为什么它被称为特定的家庭
And then the socket stuff isn't even necessarily referred to the internet the Internet
然后套接字的东西甚至不一定被称为互联网上网
And so there's a more specific one called a socket or underscore in
因此，有一个更具体的称为套接字或下划线
That is used for IPv4 sockets
那用于IPv4套接字
Well not IPv6
不是IPv6
And so in particular it fills in fields one is called the port which as I mentioned is 16 bits
所以特别是它填写了一个被称为端口的字段，正如我所提到的那样是16位
And then the IP address
然后是IP地址
The 4 byte IP address both of which are in
两个都在的4字节IP地址
Even if you're running the software on a x86 machine
即使你在x86计算机上运行该软件
These should be in big endian order
这些应该是大端序
And you'll see that this is what I mean that this is sort of a
你会发现这就是我的意思，这就是一种
C version of subtyping if you know something like C++ or java
如果你知道像C ++或java这样的东西，那就是C版的子类型
Or you know a language with type inheritance
或者你知道具有类型继承的语言
That you can think of it as a sockaddr_in a sort of a subclass of a sockaddr
你可以把它想象成一个sockaddr，它是一个sockaddr的子类
Right it has more information it's compatible with
它拥有更多与之兼容的信息
But has more information than a socket
但是有比socket更多的信息
And then there's another type of for IPv6 has a different kind of
然后还有另一种类型的IPv6有不同的类型
Struck that they fill in for its information
打动他们填写信息
And then they pat it out with 8 bytes of zeros
然后他们用8个字节的零填充它
Just because this particular protocol doesn't require the full 16 bytes
仅仅因为这个特定的协议不需要完整的16个字节
Okay so this is sort of what it looks like to operate a full-blown Client-server system from a programmers perspective
好的，这就是从程序员的角度来看，运行一个完整的客户端 - 服务器系统的样子
And we're going to for the rest of today and all of Thursday go through all these steps
我们将在今天的剩余时间内完成所有这些步骤
And you as a programmer are actually going to have to understand each of these steps
作为程序员，你实际上必须了解每个步骤
What they do?what they mean?And how to use them
他们做了什么？他们的意思是什么？以及如何使用它们
The good news is there's some pretty standard patterns here
好消息是这里有一些非常标准的模式
And so you can often grab some existing code say out of the book to use that will make this not as painful as it might look
因此，你可以经常抓住一些现有的代码，从书中说出使用，这将使它不像它看起来那么痛苦
So but the overall idea of this this picture then is
所以，这个图片的总体思路是
Sorry kick it used to fit my remote doesn't work
抱歉踢它以适合我的遥控器不起作用
On the the right hand side refers to the steps that the server has to go through
在右侧是指服务器必须经历的步骤
And the left hand side is what the client does
而左手边是客户所做的
So the upper right is what it takes to set up a server
所以右上角是设置服务器所需的
That is then a program that's running there
那是一个在那里运行的程序
Ready to receive connections  from a client and perform various services
准备好接收来自客户端的连接并执行各种服务
And so obviously before the client can do anything the server has to exist
显然，在客户端可以执行任何操作之前，服务器必须存在
So that has to be the first step in setting things up
所以这必须是设置的第一步
And then we have to...we'll fire up a cert a client that will make use of this service
然后我们必须......我们将启动一个将使用此服务的客户证书
And then there'll be what's referred to as a session
然后就会有一个被称为会话的东西
Meaning a kind of back and forth communication between the client and server
意味着客户端和服务器之间的一种来回通信
Doing whatever they're going to do,this is not specific to any particular application
做任何他们要做的事情，这不是特定于任何特定的应用程序
And like I said it will involve you'll see rio_ remember those who are reliable I/O
就像我说的那样，你会看到rio_记得那些可靠的I / O.
Functions we talked about as part of the UNIX I/O
我们作为UNIX I / O的一部分讨论过的函数
So it's a way to read and write in a room and handle some of the quirks of low-level I/O
因此，这是一种在房间中读写的方法，并处理一些低级I / O的怪癖
But basically this is sending and receiving messages over the internet
但基本上这是通过互联网发送和接收消息
And then once that's done
然后一旦完成
Typically then the client will close its connection sort of equivalent of hanging up its phone
通常情况下，客户端将关闭其连接等同于挂断其电话
And say ok I'm done
说好的我已经完成了
And then sometime later or maybe never depending on what kind of web you know service this is
然后某个时候或者可能永远不会取决于你知道服务的网络类型
If the server wants to shut down
如果服务器想要关闭
It has its own a collection of calls that it makes to stop that service
它有自己的一系列调用来阻止该服务
So anyways just to kind of give you the landscape of what this picture means
所以无论如何只是为了给你这个图片的意义
So we're going to sort of jump into
所以我们要跳进去
The middle this the top level up and we'll focus
中间这是顶级，我们将关注
Actually which will we focus on
实际上我们将关注哪些
Well we'll talk to some level in parallel
那么我们会在某种程度上并行谈论
Because there's a lot of commonality as you can see between what goes on with the server and what goes on with the client
因为你可以看到服务器发生的事情与客户端发生的事情之间存在很多共性
Yeah and so actually the top level call this one called getaddrinfo is the way that
是的，实际上顶级调用这个名为getaddrinfo的方式就是这样
It sort of...
有点......
Initiate things and actually does the lookup to map from a domain name to a IP address
启动事物并实际执行查找以从域名映射到IP地址
So we'll cover that later
所以我们稍后会介绍
So the first step in on either side then and creating a connection is a call to a function called socket
因此，在任何一方创建连接的第一步是调用一个名为socket的函数
And the reason I wanted to blackboard was to help you keep track of this
我想黑板的原因是帮助你跟踪这个
So the first call is a doesn't do much
所以第一次打电话是做不了多少
Oh and that's why the function call is socket
哦，这就是函数调用是socket的原因
But the
但是
It only happens within the application
它只发生在应用程序中
It doesn't make a use of any part of the operating system doesn't send anything over the network
它不会使用操作系统的任何部分，也不会通过网络发送任何内容
And the idea is to basically say hey I want to create a socket
而这个想法基本上就是说我想要创建一个套接字
And it's given three arguments
它有三个论点
The first two which is AF_INET
前两个是AF_INET
All these upper case on names are constants that are built in or included in the various .h files that
名称上的所有这些大写都是内置或包含在各种.h文件中的常量
That you include in writing this code
你在编写此代码时包含的内容
And AF_INET just means it's a IPv4 so 32-bit addresses
而AF_INET只是意味着它是一个IPv4 32位地址
And then the second parameter is says you want a SOCK_STREAM
然后第二个参数表示你想要一个SOCK_STREAM
And that refers to a TCP connection
这指的是TCP连接
It's referred to as a stream connection because like I said you get to send as many bytes as you like a stream of bytes
它被称为流连接，因为正如我所说，你可以发送尽可能多的字节流
Either direction
无论哪个方向
And then
接着
Zero protocol
零协议
Well I guess it must not be very interesting because I set it to zero
嗯，我想它一定不是很有趣，因为我把它设置为零
So we don't need to do anything in this particular case
所以我们不需要在这种特殊情况下做任何事情
There are man pages on this by the way which
通过这种方式有关于此的手册页
If you just tried to learn all sockets programming by reading men pages you'd go crazy
如果你只是通过阅读男性页面来尝试学习所有套接字编程，那么你会发疯
But once you kind of have the idea of it the man pages are pretty useful
但是一旦你有了它的想法，那么手册页非常有用
And then the next part
然后是下一部分
You'll see,we're looking only now on the server side is called bind
你会看到，我们现在只在服务器端看起来叫做bind
And
和
What bind does then is that specific then to a server
那么什么绑定才是特定于服务器的绑定
And now this is a make this interfaces to the kernel
现在这是一个使这个接口连接到内核
It says I want to
它说我想
Designate which IP address
指定哪个IP地址
And let me just...
让我......
So I'm going to cheat a little bit and let me by making sure I don't say anything that's not true
所以我要欺骗一点，让我确保我不说任何不真实的东西
Yeah I'm right sorry
是的，我很对不起
I just want to make sure
我只是想确定一下
Bind actually
实际上绑定
Tells you
告诉你
Oh excuse me
哦，对不起
You'll see that a socket the call to socket returns an int
你将看到套接字对套接字的调用返回一个int
But it's what it's returning is a file descriptor remember we said that
但是它返回的是文件描述符，记得我们说过
If you refer to a file a low-level file just by an integer id typically a small integer value
如果仅通过整数id引用文件低级文件，通常是一个小整数值
There's some standard ones for standard in,standard out,standard error
标准输入，标准输出，标准错误有一些标准
And then beyond that they're just assigned incrementally
除此之外，他们只是逐步分配
So socket will return a number
所以socket会返回一个数字
That you then refer used to refer to this as a file
然后你引用用于将其称为文件
So bind then you've pass in that the name of your socket file descriptor
所以绑定然后你传递了你的套接字文件描述符的名称
And you provide a whether is a socketaddr int
并且你提供了一个是否是socketaddr int
SA and I'm using the the notation
SA和我正在使用符号
SA as a shortcut for sockaddr struct sockaddr
SA作为sockaddr struct sockaddr的快捷方式
And then you have to also say what the length of the address is
然后你还要说出地址的长度是多少
So in the case of IPv4 that would be four
因此，在IPv4的情况下，将是四个
But you don't usually use that number directly there's a
但是你通常不会直接使用那个号码
We'll talk about it but that top-level call called gedit or addr info
我们将讨论它，但顶层调用称为gedit或addr信息
As a relatively new api that was created and in this addition to the book but not in previous ones
作为一个相对较新的api，它是在本书中添加的，而不是之前的
Become the now the standard way that you get all the parameters that you're supposed to pass into all these different calls
成为现在标准的方式，你得到你应该传递给所有这些不同的电话的所有参数
And the idea of it then is it's a pretty small adjustment to then write code that's good for either IPv4 or IPv6
然后它的想法是，这是一个非常小的调整，然后编写对IPv4或IPv6有利的代码
So you don't normally give the actual number from that you get it from another place and passage it
因此，你通常不会给出实际的数字，而是从另一个地方获得它并通过它
So binding then
那么绑定呢
It's a kernel call
这是一个内核调用
That designates which particular service
这指定了哪种特定服务
This program is going to be hosting
这个计划将主持
But which will be the server for and that's given by its port number
但是它的服务器是由端口号给出的
And then the next step is to
然后下一步是
To listen and that's just a call that says
听，这只是一个电话说
That will now convert this socket to a listening socket which you need as a server
现在，它将此套接字转换为你需要作为服务器的侦听套接字
So it's a way of telling the kernel that this will be
所以这是告诉内核这将是一种方式
It will be a server sar
这将是一个服务器sar
So obviously bind and listen are related ideas
显然，绑定和倾听是相关的想法
But you have to do both steps and in that particular order to create a listening socket or one for a server
但是你必须按照特定的顺序执行这两个步骤来创建一个侦听套接字或一个用于服务器的套接字
And then the final part of that to operate us is to say except
然后，操作我们的最后一部分是说除外
And
和
Oh that means okay now we've established this now I'm actually ready to receive phone calls
哦，这意味着好了，现在我们已经建立了这个我现在准备好接听电话了
Is essentially what it says is this is the final step to say
基本上它说的是这是最后一步
Okay this one's ready to accept connection requests
好的，这个已经准备好接受连接请求了
It has a similar
它有类似的
Set of arguments to sock it is sock it
袜子的一组参数是袜子
But slight difference
但略有不同
And now the interesting thing is acceptable return
而现在有趣的事情是可以接受的回报
Yet another file descriptor
又一个文件描述符
I'll so the first file descriptor is the sort of generic
我会这样，第一个文件描述符就是那种泛型
Accept and base basically except we'll
除了我们之外，基本上接受和基础
Just hang there and wait until some client makes a connection
只需挂起并等到某个客户端建立连接
And when it does then it will set up a new socket
当它发生时，它将设置一个新的套接字
And a new with a new file descriptor that then the server communicates to the client via that one
然后是一个带有新文件描述符的新文件，然后服务器通过该文件描述符与客户端通信
And I'll talk about why it's a different file descriptor in just a second
我将在一秒钟内讨论为什么它是一个不同的文件描述符
Okay over on the client side goes through similar steps of socket
好吧，在客户端方面经历了socket的类似步骤
But it doesn't have to bind or listen or accept because this is a client
但它不必绑定，倾听或接受，因为这是一个客户端
And instead what it does is it makes a call to connect
而它所做的就是呼叫连接
So let me finish this off
所以让我完成这个
So these are all on this the server side
所以这些都在服务器端
And on the client side
在客户端
It will make a call to connect
它将拨打电话进行连接
From a client side is to set up a connection to server
从客户端来说是建立与服务器的连接
And so
所以
It's arguments it's a little easier to understand how connect to work
它的论点是，更容易理解连接是如何工作的
So in particular
特别是
The call to socket that was made beforehand returns a file descriptor
事先调用socket会返回一个文件描述符
And what this says is I want to on that particular using that particular socket
这就是我想要使用特定套接字的特定内容
Connect to this gives a combination of an address and a port number
连接到此给出了地址和端口号的组合
And it has to give this address length which I said like I said as before
它必须给出这个地址长度，就像我之前说过的那样
It's usually that number is filled in using the return value of of getaddrinfo
通常使用getaddrinfo的返回值填充该数字
But that's sort of the equivalent of poisoning the core
但这相当于中毒核心
And it returns just a code which is
它只返回一个代码
Whether the connection was successful or not
连接是否成功
So let me just talk about these different ports and
那么让我来谈谈这些不同的端口和
What it all means when you setup a connection
设置连接时这意味着什么
So when the
所以当
The server went through bind and listen
服务器经历了绑定和监听
It created a listening port from that
它创建了一个监听端口
Which is the one that it's listening for connection requests on
它正在侦听连接请求的那个
And then the client when it called socket it was given a particular file descriptor for that socket
然后客户端在调用socket时为该套接字提供了一个特定的文件描述符
And it sends out a connection request
它发出连接请求
That goes out over the network
这通过网络发出
And lands at the server and then the kernel hands that off to the program that's running on that particular port
然后登陆服务器，然后内核将其移交给在该特定端口上运行的程序
And hands it off to the that call will be handled by the accept
并将其交给该电话将由接受处理
Call to accept by the server
呼叫服务器接受
And then as I mentioned except actually returns a new file descriptor
然后正如我所提到的，除了实际返回一个新的文件描述符
Which the server will then use as its connection point to this particular client
然后，服务器将使用哪个服务器作为其与此特定客户端的连接点
And the theory of that is you want to be able to in general
而那个理论就是你想要的
As a server be handling multiple clients at the same time
作为服务器同时处理多个客户端
But if I'm communicating with Google or amazon
但如果我正在与谷歌或亚马逊进行沟通
You should be able to do so at the same time
你应该能够同时这样做
So you want a possibility of from a single host to be able to serve multiple clients
因此，你希望单个主机能够为多个客户端提供服务
And that's why they're all assigned different file descriptors at the server end for that particular connection
这就是为什么他们在服务器端为该特定连接分配了不同的文件描述符
So you can think of it as the listening file descriptor is just listening for incoming requests for connections
因此，你可以将其视为侦听文件描述符只是侦听传入的连接请求
But once it sets up a session and communicates back and forth
但是一旦它建立了一个会话并来回沟通
Those are going through different ports on the server side of things or different file descriptors I'm sorry
那些通过服务器端的不同端口或不同的文件描述符我很抱歉
Same port different file descriptors
相同端口的不同文件描述符
From the software that's running on the server
从服务器上运行的软件
Okay and then during the actual communication then as I mentioned it uses reads and writes
好的，然后在实际通信期间，然后正如我所提到的，它使用读写
As a way to send and receive messages
作为发送和接收消息的方式
And that goes on for as long as
这种情况一直持续下去
You know and according to whatever low level particular protocol is being supported by this application
你知道并且根据此应用程序支持的任何低级别特定协议
And then
接着
In the end then when the client the
到底那时客户端了
Client is done it causes a request
客户端完成它会导致请求
And what that looks like from the server end is it tries to read from a file
从服务器端看起来是什么，它试图从文件中读取
And it receives an end of file a signal instead
并且它接收文件的结尾而不是信号
And that tells the server okay this particular connection is gone
这告诉服务器好了这个特定的连接消失了
And so
所以
Now it will close that particular one as this picture shows here
现在它将关闭那个特定的一个，如图所示
Potentially the server could loop back around
服务器可能会循环回来
And accept a connection from another program and in fact
并接受来自另一个程序的连接
This can be done,this is what we call a serial or a internet
这可以做到，这就是我们所说的串口或互联网
A serial server where can only manage one connection request at a time
一个串行服务器，一次只能管理一个连接请求
And when we get later in the course and we stock talk about multi threading
当我们稍后进入课程时，我们会谈论多线程
We'll be able to set it up,so this thing can start accepting requests for another connection
我们将能够进行设置，因此这件事可以开始接受另一个连接的请求
Even while it's handling one particular client
即使它正在处理一个特定的客户端
But anyways what it will look like is the server will read
但无论如何它将是什么样的服务器将读取
The attempt to read that we'll get an end of file it will close that particular connection
尝试读取我们将获得文件结束它将关闭该特定连接
And it will go back and it will accept a new connection from a new client
它将返回，它将接受来自新客户端的新连接
Okay I'm going to jump ahead and actually start talking about some slides from
好的，我要继续前进，然后开始谈论一些幻灯片
That we're if you look online they're actually from a Thursday's lecture  because
如果你在网上看，我们实际上是在周四的讲座上，因为
There's a lot of ground to cover in that lecture and I'd like to get a little head start
在那次演讲中有很多理由可以覆盖，我想先了解一下
So I mentioned this
所以我提到了这个
This function called get a door info which is sort of the modern way in C at least to find information about
这个函数被称为获取门信息，这是C中的现代方式，至少可以找到有关的信息
That deals with all the funkiness of host names host addresses
这涉及主机名主机地址的所有功能
All the conventions about ports and some of these various structures and things like that
所有关于端口的约定和一些这样的各种结构和类似的东西
And the advantage of doing it this way instead of the old way
以这种方式做到这一点的优势，而不是旧的方式
Is first of all now it sort of unifies IPv4 and IPv6 have very similar looking interfaces
首先，现在它有点统一IPv4和IPv6具有非常相似的外观
And it's fairly easy to write code that can handle either
编写可以处理的代码也相当容易
And the other was there is problems with these old ones that they were designed in an ear before multi-threading
另一个是这些旧的问题，他们是在多线程之前设计的耳朵
And so they have various statically allocated buffers
因此他们有各种静态分配的缓冲区
Which gave a lot of bad conditions that you had to watch out for in writing code
这给了你编写代码时必须注意的许多不良条件
And we're prone to errors of various sorts
而且我们容易出现各种各样的错误
And so this new format it's actually harder to use in many levels
所以这种新格式实际上很难在很多层面上使用
Because it can't hide away as many details as it used to
因为它无法隐藏尽可能多的细节
But it has the advantage it works better in a multi-threaded environment
但它具有在多线程环境中更好地工作的优点
The other thing that makes it hard is it's trying to be sort of the kitchen sink of protocol managers
另一件令人困难的事情是它试图成为协议管理者的厨房水槽
And that makes it a little bit nasty and messy
这使它有点讨厌和凌乱
And so we're only going to sort of focus in on the parts that we really need to make use of for this course
因此，我们只关注我们真正需要在本课程中使用的部分
So in particular there's this function called getaddrinfo
所以特别是这个函数名为getaddrinfo
Where the information you're passing is a host
你传递的信息是主机
Which can be either a...it's a string as it shows most these are care stars are actual real strings not fake strings
这可能是...它是一个字符串，因为它显示大多数这些是关心明星是实际真正的字符串而不是假字符串
It used to be back in the old days
它曾经是过去的时代
You use char* of generic pointer because there weren't void*
你使用泛型指针的char *，因为没有void *
But these are actual strings
但这些都是实际的字符串
So you give the name like the domain name of a host or you can give the dotted decimal name
因此，你可以给出类似主机域名的名称，也可以给出点分十进制名称
But written as you know sequence of characters one to eight dot so forth
但是如果你知道字符序列一到八点那么写
A service for example that this is IPv4 TCP service
例如，这是IPv4 TCP服务的服务
Some other information that's associated with this particular connection they refer to as hints
与此特定连接相关联的其他一些信息，它们称为提示
Because again this is trying to be a very generic looking call
因为这又是一个非常通用的呼叫
And then you pass it in a pointer and it will fill in and return back a pointer to a data structure
然后在指针中传递它，它将填充并返回指向数据结构的指针
Which is essentially the way it's returning results back to you
这基本上是它将结果返回给你的方式
And then associated with that is a called free adder info that will then deallocate this space
然后与之关联的是一个名为free free adder的信息，然后将释放此空间
That's used by this data structure from the result
这个数据结构从结果中使用了它
And then there's one called getaddrinfo string error
然后有一个名为getaddrinfo字符串错误
Which lets you interpret the various error codes that get created by this routine of the value that it returns
这使你可以解释由它返回的值的此例程创建的各种错误代码
So
所以
Let's just look a little about this and
我们来看看这个和
So the result that's returned by getaddrinfo is a link twist
所以getaddrinfo返回的结果是链接扭曲
Oh that is null terminated just like...most link lists are
哦，就像...大多数链接列表都是空终止
Where it gives some combination of the name
它给出了名称的某种组合
Of this particular
这个特别的
Some naming information for the first top-level one is the
第一个顶级的一些命名信息是
What I showed you the canonical name for this particular IP address
我向你展示了此特定IP地址的规范名称
And then it gives some address information which is
然后它给出了一些地址信息
You know an IPv4 them that will encode the IP address
你知道一个IPv4将编码IP地址
And as a next pointer to change this link list together
并作为下一个指针一起更改此链接列表
And so this is actually one interesting thing about this is it sort of...
所以这实际上是一个有趣的事情是它有点......
This link voice together many too many mapping potentially of of names
这个链接可以将很多可能的名称映射到一起
So if I give for example google.com
所以如果我举个例子google.com
It will return a link list of all
它将返回所有的链接列表
However many or you saw with twitter it was returning about four different addresses
然而很多人或者你在推特上看到它返回了四个不同的地址
So this will return actually five missed entries the first will be the canonical name
所以这将实际返回五个错过的条目，第一个将是规范名称
And then it will give each of the four IP addresses
然后它将给出四个IP地址中的每一个
That's relevant at this particular time
这在这个特定的时间是相关的
And then you as a programmer
然后你作为程序员
Then sort of walk this list you step down this list and typically
然后，按照此列表的顺序走一步，通常是这个列表
Try to use each address one after the other
尝试一个接一个地使用每个地址
And if you fail on one then you try the next and try the next until you hit the end of the list and then you say loops
如果你失败，那么你尝试下一个并尝试下一个，直到你到达列表的末尾，然后你说循环
Can't do it
做不到
And that goes whether you're writing a client or a server
无论你是在编写客户端还是服务器，都可以
So that addrinfo
所以addrinfo
Let's look back at what that is
让我们回顾一下那是什么
Oh so
哦，所以
Addrinfo then is what gets returned is a list of addrinfo struct
Addrinfo然后返回的是addrinfo结构列表
And so the addrinfo struck contains various fields
因此addrinfo hitck包含各种字段
Which talks about what type of data is here
其中讨论了这里的数据类型
What type of socket is it
它是什么类型的插座
What its canonical name is how long are its addresses you saw that it's an argument to some of the calls
它的规范名称是它的地址有多长，你看到它是一些调用的参数
A pointer to a sockaddr struct
指向sockaddr结构的指针
That's the way that is encoded for IPv
这就是为IPv编码的方式
What we've already seen sock adders is a sort of low-level data structure that gets used
我们已经看到的袜子加法器是一种被使用的低级数据结构
And then an next pointer to chain the link list together
然后是将链接列表链接在一起的下一个指针
And so you'll see some of these are the arguments
所以你会看到其中一些是争论
That then you will use to pass into the other functions like bind and with list links and connect
那么你将使用传递到其他函数，如bind和list链接和connect
And then there's another version called getnameinfo
然后是另一个名为getnameinfo的版本
Which you use when you've got an IP address
当你有一个IP地址时使用的
And you want to find what is its domain name
你想找到它的域名是什么
And because you remember that mapping is also potentially a one-to-many
而且因为你记得映射也可能是一对多的
There can be multiple domain names associated with it
可以有多个与之关联的域名
And so it has a similar general thing
所以它有类似的一般性
We'll just look right now it getaddrinfo
我们现在就看看它是getaddrinfo
So just as an example of how you'd write code to make use of this
所以，这只是一个如何编写代码来使用它的例子
Essentially just as a way of probing the DNS server
基本上只是一种探测DNS服务器的方式
Is I want to set up an argument a call to getaddrinfo
我想设置一个参数来调用getaddrinfo
Where the string I'm going to pass the name is
我要传递名字的字符串是
Whatever I type in there to this application to main
无论我输入什么，这个应用程序主要
And it just for hints just passes a bunch of zeros
它只是为了提示只是传递了一堆零
And listp again these are this will just be a pointers
而listp再次这些只是一个指针
That I haven't actually
我实际上并没有
Oh okay so you'll notice hints is actually a struct itself
哦好的，所以你会注意到提示实际上是一个结构本身
Whereas listp and *p are just listsp andp are just pointers to structs
listp和* p只是listsp，而isp只是指向结构的指针
They don't have any allocated data
他们没有任何分配的数据
So the hints I'm just going to fill in that struct with all zeros
所以提示我只是用全零来填充该结构
Because I don't really need to provide any hints
因为我真的不需要提供任何提示
I am telling it that I want an IPv6 TCP connection here
我告诉它我想要一个IPv6 TCP连接
And then
接着
So what it will do is it will return back
那么它会做什么就会回来
What returns an error code
什么返回错误代码
But it will fill in returned to me a pointer
但它会填补给我一个指针
To a this link twist data structure I showed before
对于此链接扭曲数据结构我之前显示
And now I can step through that list
现在我可以逐步完成这个清单
Using standard linked list code and make calls to the getnameinfo function which will return back domain names
使用标准链表代码并调用getnameinfo函数，该函数将返回域名
And then when it's all done I have to free up that whisk that got returned otherwise all great memory stuff
然后当它全部完成时，我必须释放那些返回的拂尘，否则所有伟大的记忆内容
So just as a demo
所以就像一个演示
What I'm
我是什么
On oh host info sorry
哦主持人信息抱歉
Ah so you can think of it this is like
啊所以你可以想到这就像
A not very fancy implementation of nslookup
一个不太花哨的nslookup实现
So the kind of stuff we already saw before but let's
所以我们之前已经看过的东西，但是让我们看看
All it's returning are the different addresses and one of the things that I found curious is
所有它返回的是不同的地址和我发现好奇的事情之一
It returns them in the same order all the time
它始终以相同的顺序返回它们
Instead of within a slow cup it kept changing it
而不是在缓慢的杯子里，它不断改变它
And I think that has to do with caching
我认为这与缓存有关
No that changed
没有改变
I know it's kind of interesting if it's
我知道如果它是有趣的
It you might want to play with this code, it's kind of you can see what's going on in different places
你可能想要使用此代码，你可以看到在不同的地方发生了什么
And so you can see though that it's
所以你可以看到它
Basically getting the same kind of information
基本上得到同样的信息
That you would from nslookup it's really just creating the DNS server to do this
你想从nslookup那里创建DNS服务器就可以了
But that's the start of what some of this code looks like
但这是一些代码看起来的开始
One of the things you
你做的事情之一
By the way when you're writing your own code,you often make use of what's called localhost
顺便说一句，当你编写自己的代码时，你经常使用所谓的localhost
And that always just refers to the machine that you're running on it
而这总是指你正在运行的机器
Always has this particular IP address
始终拥有此特定IP地址
So that address just refers to the machine and as a programmer
所以这个地址只是指机器和程序员
You do all your testing on one machine
你在一台机器上进行所有测试
You just set up both the client and the server on the same machine and play with it so
你只需在同一台计算机上设置客户端和服务器，然后使用它
Localhost is a very useful way of doing code development
Localhost是一种非常有用的代码开发方式
And if this shows you can request host info for others
如果这表明你可以请求其他人的主机信息
Thanksgiving and you can also by the way
感恩节，你也可以顺便说一下
Always give a dotted decimal address
始终给出点分十进制地址
And I'm just making it up here
而我只是在这里弥补
What and it's not very interesting because it returns back the same address
什么，它不是很有趣，因为它返回相同的地址
It's more interesting to run nslookup on that
运行nslookup更有趣
So
所以
That just gives you a sense
这只是给你一个感觉
And as you've seen this code is pretty messy stuff to work with there's a lot of struck
正如你所看到的那样，这段代码非常麻烦，可以解决很多问题
So you have to initialize,you don't initialize you pass pointers
所以你必须初始化，你没有初始化你传递指针
And so the code always looks a bit crufty
所以代码总是看起来有点夸张
But that sort of the the interfaces it exists
但它存在的那种接口
And you'll just have to get somewhat comfortable with it
而且你只需要对它感到满意
So that will do us for today then thanks
那么今天我们会这样做，谢谢